Engr. Muhammad Zeeshan Qureshi



Contact

Address:

House No 264 Street No 4 Sanghar Town Gangal Rawalpindi

Phone:

- +92 317 5621704
- +92 345 9716922

Email:

zeeshan qureshi 1@hotmail.c om zeeshanq05@gmail.com

Portfolio

LinkedIn:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/engr-muhammad-zeeshan-qureshi-0a09a3b5/

Languages

English Urdu

Summary

Project Manager and Technical Team Lead managing multiplatform teams to provide all-in-one software. Technical expert working in field for over 7 years. Experienced in all stages of software development cycle for dynamic web projects. Well-versed in numerous programming languages including PHP, Laravel, JavaScript, Oracle, Python, NodeJs, ReactJs, Matlab, MySQL, MongoDb, Ms.SQL. Strong background in programming, database development and team management. Excellent academic background with vast knowledge of current technologies.

Skill Highlights

- Excellent Programmer
- Complex Problem Solver
- Team Leader
- API Development
- Server Configuration
- Strong
 Communication Skills
- Data Analyst
- Algorithm Creation
- Artificial Intelligence

- Service-focused
- Cooperative Team Worker
- Third Party Service Integrator
- Server Administration
- Customer Dealing and Satisfaction
- Model Creations in Machine Learning
- Code and Query Optimization
- Workflow Creation

Experience

Technical Team Lead - 03/2022 to present **Innovo Technologies, Islamabad Pakistan**

- Management of multiple platform teams working for projects.
- Analysis, Planning and Supervision of projects.
- Ease working of inter platform working of teams.
- Project include python, frontend (ReactJs), backend (Laravel/Lumen) and mobile [Android (Kotlin, Java), IOS, Flutter]. Managing all with optimized performance of workflow.
- Managing flow of CI/CD for staged testing and beta testing using dockers.
- Deployment of projects on client environment and managing its workflow for streamline usage.
- Monitoring performance of team and reporting to upper management.
- Conducting Training sessions for teams to improve skillset of my team.
- Integration of IOT Devices with project to fulfill requirements of client.

Skills

Team Management

Unit Testing

Socket Programming

Artificial Intelligence

Machine Learning

Data Mining

Data Analysis (Tableau, Spreadsheets, CSV, XML, JSON, Databases)

Programming Languages

PHP, MVC, Web Services, Laravel, Lumen, Yii Framework

Javascript/JQuery/JQuery Widgets, Ajax, Extensionjs, AngularJs, ReactJs, NodeJs

Python, Matlab, JAVA

MySQL, Ms SQL, Oracle, PDO, SQLite, MongoDb

Certifications

MCSE-(Microsoft Windows Server 2003) and ISA Server Workshop.

LINUX Server and Asterisk Voice Over IP (VOIP) Server Workshop

Other Experience

Attock Refinery Limited, Rawalpindi – 06/2015 to 08/2015

Hobbies

Programming, Cricket, Football, Computer Games

Sr. Software Engineer - 07/2016 to 03/2022 Caresoft Technologies, Rawalpindi Pakistan

- Develop project concepts and maintain optimal workflow.
- Discuss requirements with senior management & customer and propose innovative & satisfying solutions.
- Work with project manager to manage large, complex design projects for corporate clients.
- Work as Programming Team Lead and assign tasks to junior engineers.
- Complete detailed programming and development tasks for front end public and internal websites as well as challenging back-end server code.
- Dealing with technically challenging scenarios irrespective of any programming language barrier.

Education

Master of Science: Software Engineering – 2018-2021

National University of Science & Technology (NUST), MCS

Rawalpindi (3.75/4.00)

Bachelor of Science: Software Engineering – 2012-2016

University of Engineering and Technology (UET) Taxila Pakist

University of Engineering and Technology (UET), Taxila Pakistan (3.90/4.00)

Publications

- "Efficient Prediction of Missed Clinical Appointment Using Machine Learning", Computational and Mathematical Methods in Medicine, vol. 2021, Article ID 2376391, 10 pages, 2021. https://doi.org/10.1155/2021/2376391
- "Capturing Users Requirements Using a Data Mining Approach," 2021 International Conference on Communication Technologies (ComTech), 2021, pp. 49-54, doi: 10.1109/ComTech52583.2021.9616939.

Notable Work

- Braintreemd Medical EHR System. Provide all medical services from appointment till discharge of patient.
- **AQGNow** for Alqaryan. Delivery system that provide real time tracking of vehicles, drivers and material transfer details.
- Yard Management System. Solution to manage internal working of yards from scrap to resale raw.
- Scrap Station. Marketplace system that connect scrap sellers to scrap buyer industries.
- Waleed Hospital (eHMS) Solution for Clinic
- Third Party **Product Delivery System**. Uber like solution.
- TeleHospital. (Provide to local hospitals in Pakistan)
- Detailed Analysis of Real Time Patient Appointments Using Machine Learning. [MS Thesis]
- Human Detection and Location Tagging From Live Stream
 Videos [BS FYP]